And the next part, what we want to do is we have these first 1,000 users and basically,
接下来 我们将使用前 1000 个用户
we're going to try using FunkSVD on that.
将对这 1000 个用户应用 FunkSVD
So, if we pull the first 1,000 users,
提取前 1,000 个用户
we are doing 20 iterations and it says this will take some time.
迭代 20 次 需要一段运行时间
So, do 20 iterations.
迭代 20 次
So, here you can see we're going to do this with 1,000
我们提取了 1000 个用户
users but you could imagine doing this with the full data frame,
当然也可以使用整个 DataFrame
this would work, it's
这就要看你的机器计算能力
just a function of what your compute power is and how long this might take.
以及你能接受多长的运行时间了
We're starting to see some results come in
这里出现了一些结果
and we can see that things are moving in the right direction,
这些值符合我们的预期
and we have our first mean squared error of 23 and then it almost happening.
第一个均方误差为 23
Now, it's done the seventh. So, we'll see what happens
然后是 7 点多的值我们看看到第 20 次迭代时
by the 20th iteration but hopefully,
结果将是多少
you're also seeing things that are moving in the right direction.
希望你的结果也符合预期
So, my results are finished running.
我的结果都出来了
You can see they're still may be more of an error than we want
误差越来越小
here and we could continue running this to probably get that down even lower.
我们可以继续运行 直到这些值更低
It looks like it's still reducing at a pretty reasonable rate,
可以看出 值依然以合理的规律下降
but let's go ahead and move forward and learn from what's happening here.
但是我们直接从已经发生的情况中推断吧
So, the first thing we should look at is this first 1,000 users
首先应该看看这前 1000 个用户
and see how many missing values are sort of in that particular matrix.
看看该矩阵中缺少多少个值
So, if you didn't look at the header of it, yourself,
如果你没有自己查看表格标题的话
I'm just using the same counts non-zero part that we had before.
提醒下 我使用的是之前的非零计数代码
So, how many of the actual ratings exist in the first 1,000 users? So, that looks okay.
前 1,000 个用户中实际有多少个评分？有这么多
Then, how many ratings did we make for
我们对多少个实际上没有评分的
user-movie pairs that didn't actually have any rating?
用户-电影对预测了评分？
So, essentially, this should be the shape.
计算方法是 shape.()
What I was trying to do earlier,
和之前一样
so if I take the number of rows times the number of columns and
用行数乘以列数
then subtract the num_ratings,
再减去 num_ratings
this is basically how many possible ratings we could've made?
这部分表示我们可能会获得的评分数量
This is the number of ratings that actually existed
这部分表示 DataFrame 中的
in the data frame for us to learn from. Let's free run this.
实际评分数量运行下代码
You can see there's a ton of missing values here and we only
可以看出 我们缺少了很多值
had 11,000 ratings to work from so this is a very sparse matrix.
只有大约 11,000 个评分 所以这个矩阵很稀疏
So, let's just go ahead and look at the first 1,000 users.
我们来看看前 1,000 个用户
Yes, so you can see it's basically all Nans.
基本上都是 NaN
If we look at the number of rows and the number of columns,
我们来看看行数和列数
it's 1,000 users by 31,000 movies.
它有 1,000 个用户和 31,000 部电影
Essentially, it's just a ton of missing values with only 10,000 ratings in there.
缺少了大量值 只有大约 10,000 个评分
You can imagine this took some time to run through because
运行时间比较久
we're going through each element in that matrix.
因为我们需要查看矩阵中的每个元素
So, finally, we can check.
最后检查一下
It looks like my results are ready.
看来我的结果没问题
But this is a great step because we don't need to use the built-in,
这一步很重要 因为我们不需要内置函数
we built our own function that can now take
可以自己构建一个函数
any matrix no matter how sparse it is and can compute
现在能够传入无论多稀疏的矩阵
ratings for user-movie pairs what they didn't originally exists and we can make
并且能够计算本身不存在的用户-电影对评分
sure that learning in the right ways and we'll get ratings.
我们能够确保学习方向是对的 并且将获得评分
So, by taking the dot product of these two items,
通过计算这两项的点积
we can now obtain a prediction for any user-movie.
我们现在能够获得任何用户-电影的预测值
So if I grab the index of
如果获取某个用户的索引
some user and the index of some movie and I take the dot product of
以及某部电影的索引
those two things that will give me the prediction for
然后计算这两项的点积
that user-movie even if that user has never actually interacted with that movie.
我们将能预测该用户-电影评分 即使用户从未实际与该电影互动过
An incredible thing and we can see that it's doing well.
这项功能太强大了 并且执行效果很好